字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
放大
主演：瓦妮莎·雷德格瑞夫
主演：萨拉·米尔斯
主演：戴维·海明斯
导演
米开朗基罗·安东尼奥尼
- 再见，我们会再来看你的  - 再见
- So long. we'll see you again.  - Goodbye.
把钱给我
Give me your money. Do it.
- 太捧了  - 谢谢
- Splendid.  - Thank you.
蓝四三九
Blue 439.
- 蓝四三九  - 我是蓝四三九，请说
- Blue 439. Over.  - Blue 439, go ahead, please. Oer.
打电话给维斯顿，说我已经在路上了，好吗？
Phone weston 0-21 9. Tell him l'm on my way, will you?
知道了，请稍候
Roger Wilco. Stand by.
- 你好，亲爱的  - 你好
- Hello, love.  - Hello.
- 把这些洗一下好吗？ - 好的
- Get that stuff developed, will you?  - Yeah.
立刻
Right away.
我在这里
Here l am.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
- 我已经准备好将近一个钟头了  - 很好
- l've been ready for nearly an hour.  - Good.
我十一点要搭乘到巴黎的飞机，所以我不能…
l'm catching a plane for Paris at 1 1 , so l can't--
不能什么了？
Can't what?
无关紧要
lt doesn't matter.
昨晚你到底跟谁在一起？
who the hell were you with last night?
雷吉
Reg.
雷吉，弄点声音好吗？
Reg, let's have some noise, can we?
很好
Right.
好的很好，就保持这样
That's good. That's good. Hold that.
雷吉
Reg.
给我好的，嗯，很好
Give it to me now. Come on. That's good.
向前，再前一点
Hunch. Hunch more.
就这样，很好
That's it. That's good.
很好，把头发弄到后面去
That's good. And the hair back. And the hair back.
非常棒，非常棒！很好，再来
That's great. That's great! That's good. More of that.
现在给我来一个，真的来一个，来吧
Now give it to me. Really give it to me. Come on, now.
尽快地，给我来吧，右边
As fast as you can, give it to me. Come on, right forward.
很好，这边这边，靠右边，手举起来
That's good. This side. This side. Lean right forward. Hand up.
很好，触摸脸，非常好
That's great. Just touch the face. That's very good.
像这样再来一次，再触摸脸
And again around this way. Touch the face again.
好的，头发真不可思议，太捧了
Good. Now the hair. Marvelous. That's great.
好的，对…头发，再一次，再一次
Good. Yes, the hair. Much more. Much more.
好了太棒了，很好，是的，再来再来
Good. Yes, that's great. That's good. Yes. And again. And again.
噢，就这样，头发弄到后面，再来很好
Oh, hold that. Hold the hair back. Again. Good.
好了，雷吉，50
Okay, Reg, 50.
躺下躺下，继续
On your back. On your back. Go on.
是的，现在真的给我，来吧
Yes. Now really give it to me. Come on.
来吧来，来，来！
Come on. work, work, work!
很好，很好，再来继续，退后退后，手臂举起来
Great. Great. And again. Go on. Back. Back. Arms up.
伸展自己，小淑女，很好
Stretch yourself, little lady. Great.
再来，继续继续
And again. Go on. Go. Go.
很好
That's great.
就这样，保持这样，真可爱
That's it. Keep it up. Lovely.
对了，就快好了，很好
Yeah, make it come. Great.
不，不，头抬起来，头抬起来
No, no, head up. Head up.
为我，亲爱的，为我
Now for me, love. For me.
来呀！来呀！对！对！对了！
Now! Now! Yes! Yes! Yes!
喂？
Hello？
Hello?
是的，请等一下
Yeah, hold on.
是彼得
lt's Peter.
喂？
Hello?
是的
Yes.
是的，我知道地方，我知道，我明白了
Yeah, l've got it somewhere. l know l have.
是的，等一下
Yeah, hold on.
雷吉，把那该死的旧货店的名字记下来，好吗？
Reg, take down the address of that bloody junk shop, would you?
啊，真是难以置信，继续
why, they're fabulous. Go on.
是的
Yeah.
是的，很好
Yeah. Great.
给你，你有得烧了
Here. You can burn that lot.
雷吉！
Reg！
Reg!
- 把小鸟们打下来，好吗？ - 好的
- Get the birds down, will you?  - Okay.
不要嚼口香糖，把它吐掉
No chewing gum. Get rid of it.
别吐到我地板上
And not on my floor.
你，手臂放下来
You, arm down.
是的
Right.
六公分[毫米/厘米]
Six millimeter.
真糟糕
Terrible.
腿再向前一点怎么样？
How about the leg a little further forward?
把头抬起来
Put the head up.
就这样，嘴张开，嗯，好，很好
Just go. Mouth open. Yes, good. Good.
不，你们都错了，再来，再想想，再想想
No, you're all wrong. Start again. Rethink it. Rethink it.
披条纹衣的，让衣服落下来，把条纹弄直了
Stripes, let the dress just fall down. Keep the stripes straight.
让手臂上啊下的
Just let your arms go up and down.
是的，很好我喜欢，我喜欢，继续
Yes, very tasty. Yes, l like it. l like it. Go on.
是的
Yeah.
好，换个位置
All right, change position.
是的
Yep.
醒醒
wake up!
你们能跟我一起工作，该谢谢你们的幸运星，知道吗？
You can thank your lucky stars you're working with me, can't you?
好的，再来一次
All right, one more.
笑一笑，来吧
And let's smile now. Come on.
笑一个
Smile.
天哪
God.
我要你们微笑啊
l asked you to smile.
怎么回事啊？
what's the matter?
你们忘了怎么笑了吗？
Have you forgotten what a smile is?
嘿？！
Hey?!
好吧，你们都累了，休息一下吧
All right, you're all tired now. Go on, relax.
我看不到你们的眼珠了，它们都眯起来了
l can't see your eyeballs anymore. They're just slits.
来吧
Go on.
把眼睛闭上
Close your eyes.
就这样
And stay like that.
这对你们有好处
lt's good for you.
把眼睛闭上
Close your eyes.
这一定有五六年了
That must be five or six years old.
我拍的时候，它们对我一点意义都没有，只有麻烦
They don't mean anything when l do them. Just a mess.
之后，我发现有些东西还是有点意思的…
Afterwards, l find something to hang on to, like that--
比如说这腿
Quite like that leg.
然后它自己显现出来了合情合理
Then it sorts itself out and adds up.
这就像是侦探故事里找到了线索一样
lt's like finding a clue in a detective story.
别问我这个，我还不知道
Don't ask me about this one. l don't know yet.
- 我能买它吗？ - 不行
- Can l buy it?  - No.
你把它给我吗？
will you give it to me?
来
There.
紧绷着脸的混蛋
Tight-faced bastard.
一幅破画都不愿卖给我
He won't float me one of his crappy paintings.
哪天晚上，我摸进来把它偷走
l'll creep down one night and knock it off.
不要停，真舒服
Don't stop, it's lovely.
你看起来很累
You look tired.
我整个晚上都在集体宿舍里
l've been all night in a doss house.
她们说有人找她们来的
They say they've been asked to come here.
- 不是我  - 事实上没人找我们来
- Not by me.  - well, we weren't exactly asked.
抱歉，我很忙
Sorry, l'm busy.
他们在楼上帮我洗一些照片，去给我拿下来
They're printing some snaps for me upstairs. Go and fetch them.
不能给我们几分钟吗？
Couldn't you give us just a couple of minutes?
几分钟？
A couple of minutes?
我连割盲肠的时间都没有
l haven't even got a couple of minutes to have my appendix out.
- 那我们可以再来吗？ - 不能
- well, when can we come then?  - Don't.
- 其他人还闭着眼睛等着？ - 是的，但是眼睛睁开了
- The others still waiting with their eyes shut?  - Yes, they're waiting, but their eyes are open.
很好
Good.
叫她们再把眼睛闭上
Tell them to shut them again.
把那包扔掉，糟糕透了
Get rid of that bag. lt's diabolical.
我们今天下午还可以再来吗？
Can we come back this afternoon?
- 你要什么？ - 随便看看
- what do you want?  - Just looking around.
这里没有使宜货，你在浪费时间
There are no cheap bargains here. You're wasting your time.
噢，我只是随便看看
well, l'll just have a look.
你到底在找什么？
what are you looking for?
- 画  - 没有画
- Pictures.  - No pictures.
什么样的画？
what kind of pictures?
- 风景画  - 抱歉，没有风景画
- Landscapes.  - Sorry, no landscapes.
卖了，都卖了
Sold. All sold.
- 你是老板吗？ - 不是，老板出去了
- You the owner?  - No, the owner is out.
可以等他吗？
Expecting him?
你在干什么？
what are you doing?
住手！住手！
Stop it! Stop it!
给我，你不能这样给人拍照
Give me those. You can't photograph people like that.
谁说我不能？
who says l can't?
我只是在工作，有些人是斗牛士，
l'm only doing my job. Some people are bullfighters...
…有些人是政治家
...some people are politicians.
我是摄影师
l'm a photographer.
这是公众场合，每个人都有权力不被打扰
This is a public place. Everyone has the right to be left in peace.
如果你被打扰了，这不是我的错
lt's not my fault if there's no peace.
知道吗，大多数女孩要我给她们拍照都得付钱
You know, most girls would pay me to photograph them.
我给你钱
l'll pay you.
我要价很高的
l overcharge.
胶卷上有我想要的其他东西
There are other things l want on the reel.
那我们怎么办？
what do we do then?
我把照片给你送去
l send you the photographs.
不，我现在就要
No, l want them now.
不！
No!
这么猴急干什么？
what's the rush?
别把事情都弄糟了，我们才刚见面
Don't let's spoil everything. we've only just met.
不，我们没见过面，你从没见过我
No, we haven't met. You've never seen me.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hello.
- 我的代表到这里来见过你了  - 是吗？
- My agent saw you about this shop.  - Did he?
是个抽雪茄的人
He's a man with a cigar.
把烟灰扔得到处都是
Throws ash everywhere.
希望我记得他
l expect l remember him.
我可能要价很高的
l probably asked for too much money.
钱总是个问题，不是吗？
Money's always a problem, isn't it?
叫他回来
Tell him to come back.
你为什么要卖它？
why are you selling?
我想试试不同的东西
l'd like to try something different.
到别的地方去
Get off somewhere.
我受够了古董
l'm fed up with antiques.
到哪去？
Get off where?
去尼泊尔
To Nepal.
尼泊尔到处都是古董
Nepal is all antiques.
是吗？
ls it?
或许我该试试去摩洛哥
Perhaps l better try Morocco.
- 多少钱？ - 什么？
- How much?  - what?
这个螺旋桨
The propeller.
你给…
You can have it for...
- 八英镑吧  - 好，成交
- ...8 pounds.  - Right. You're in business.
- 你有货车吗？ - 你现在不能拿走
- Have you got a van?  - You can't take it now.
我必须拿走
l must.
必须拿走
- 没有它我活不下去  - 真不幸
- l can't live without it.  - Hard luck.
那会让你在周六早上爱上一些很贵重的东西的
That'll teach you to fall in love with heavy things on Saturday mornings.
- 是这辆吗？ - 是的
- ls that it?  - That's it.
你不能这样待它，这不是货车
You can't treat it like that. lt's not a delivery van.
- 谁在乎呢？ - 给我
- who cares?  - Leave it to me.
会有东西出现的
Something will turn up.
是的，好吧，但是最好今天出现
Yes. All right, but it better turn up today.
蓝四三九，蓝四三九，回答
Blue 439. Blue 439. Over.
四三九，请说
439, go ahead, please. Oer.
你好，我是…
Hello, this is....
给我接弗莱克斯顿2-249沃克先生，彼得·沃克先生
Get me Flaxton 2-249. Mr. walker. Mr. Peter walker.
告诉他我去旧货店看过了，价格很高，但是会降下来的
Tell him l saw the junk shop. lt's pricey, but the kid will come down.
让他立刻打电话给她，然后…
Let him ring her right away, then...
没有人会去买它
...nobody else will get it.
知道了，请稍候
Roger Wilco. Stand by.
蓝四三九，蓝四三九，请回答
Blue 439. Blue 439. Oer.
Blue 439. Blue 439. Go ahead, echo.
蓝四三九，信息已传过去，号码已储存，你的呼叫者不喜欢它
Blue 439, message passed. The number stored. Your caller doesn't like it.
叫他塞满了
Tell him to get stuffed.
这周围的建筑怎么样？
what about all the buildings going up around the place?
这个地区已经有同性恋和狮子狗了
Already there are queers and poodles in the area.
在那里的几分钟里，我就看见了几个
l saw some in the couple of minutes l was there.
- 就像一个炸弹  - 蓝四三九，那地区有什么？
- lt'll go like a bomb. Over.  - Blue 439. What is in the area? Oer.
- 算了  - 知道了，请稍候
- Forget it. Over.  - Roger Wilco. Standing by.
你想用这些？
You want to use the lot?
你不喜欢吗？
Don't you like them?
很好啊
They're great.
我们用三到四张
we'll use three or four.
要出版吗？
Spread through the book?
不，全都不要
No. All together.
好的
Yeah.
- 一品脱  - 好的，先生
- And a pint.  - Yes, sir.
最后决定用哪张？
which one last?
这些都不用，我最后拍到难以置信的东西
None of this lot. l've got something fab for the end.
在公园里，今天早上才拍到的，稍晚就能拿到
ln a park. l only took them this morning. You'll get them later today.
非常平静，非常静寂
lt's very peaceful, very still.
书的其他部分用暴力的，这样最好了
And the rest of the book will be pretty violent, so it's best to end it like that.
是的
Yes.
这样最好
That's best.
确实很好
Rings truer.
我这个星期离开伦敦
l'm going off London this week.
为什么？
why?
这里对我一点用都没有
lt doesn't do anything for me.
是啊
Yeah.
- 我已经赶做了一些说明  - 是吗？
- l've knocked up a few captions.  - Yeah?
我受够了那些骚娘们
l'm fed up with those bloody bitches.
真希望我有上吨的钞票
l wish l had tons of money.
然后，就可以随心所欲了
Then l'd be free.
随心所欲做什么？
Free to do what?
像他一样随心所欲？
Free like him?
那个人我们认识吗？
Someone we know?
[反战游行]
[要和平，不要战争]
很好
That'll be all right.
你好，请给我接佛罗伯谢尔3-229，我只有六便士
Hello. Could you get me Frobershire 3-229, please? l've only got a sixpence.
公园一二九六号
Park 1 296.
喂，是我
Hello. lt's me.
你不是要去找赫尔利吗？
weren't you supposed to be going off to Hurley?
听着，待在那里别动，等一会打电话到我家
Listen, stay where you are. Call me soon at home.
我是来…
l've come....
我是来取照片的
l've come for the photographs.
你是怎么找到我的？
How did you manage to find me?
你住在这里吗？
Do you live here?
喝点什么吗？
Drink?
我的烂照片有什么重要的？
what's so important about my bloody pictures?
这是我的事
That's my business.
今天早上公园的光线非常好
The light was very beautiful in the park this morning.
那些照片应该很好的
Those shots should be very good.
无论如何，我需要它们
Anyway, l need them.
我的私人生活已经一团糟了，那将是个灾难，如果…
My private life's already in a mess. lt would be a disaster if....
如果怎样？
So what?
解决问题不会是个灾难
Nothing like a little disaster for sorting things out.
你摆过造型吗？
Have you ever done any modeling?
我是说时尚型的
Fashion stuff, l mean.
你很不错
You've got it.
就这样，别动
Hold that.
没有多少女孩能这样站着
Not many girls can stand as well as that.
不，谢谢！我在赶时间
No, thanks. l'm in a hurry.
你会拿到照片的
You'll get your pictures.
我保证
l promise.
我会遵守承诺
l always keep my word.
过来
Come here.
让我看看你是怎么坐的
Show me how you sit.
谁呀？
who is it?
噢，是的，没错，请稍等
Oh, yes. That's right. Hold on a second.
找我的？
ls it for me?
是我妻子
lt's my wife.
我干嘛要跟她说话？
why should l speak to her?
抱歉，亲爱的，跟我一起的小鸟不想跟你说话
Sorry, love. The bird l'm with won't talk to you.
实际上她不是我妻子
She isn't my wife, really.
我们只是有一些小孩
we just have some kids.
不
No.
没有小孩，连小孩都没有
No kids. Not even kids.
有时候，感觉好像我们有小孩
Sometimes, though, it feels as if we had kids.
她并不漂亮，她…
She isn't beautiful. She's...
很容易相处
...easy to live with.
不，她不是的
No, she isn't.
这就是我不跟她住一起的原因
That's why l don't live with her.
但是即使跟漂亮女孩们在一起…
But even with beautiful girls...
你看着她们，就这样
...you look at them, and that's that.
这就是为什么她们最终会…
That's why they always end up by....
我整天跟她们呆在一起
And l'm stuck with them all day long.
男人都一样
lt would be the same with men.
听听这个
Have a listen to this.
不，安静别动
No. Keep still. Keep still.
听，别动
Listen and keep still.
如果喜欢，你可以抽烟
You can smoke if you like.
慢慢地慢慢地
Slowly. Slowly.
跟着节拍
Against the beat.
是的
That's it.
我受不了，我太紧张了
l can't stand it. l'm nervous enough as it is.
我能喝点水吗？
Can l have some water?
我不是傻瓜，亲爱的
And l'm not a fool, love.
能把照片给我吗？
Can l have the photographs?
当然
Of course.
稍等一下
Later.
你男朋友有点过时了
Your boyfriend's a bit past it.
为什么不开出你的条件呢？
why didn't you say what you want?
穿上衣服
Get dressed.
我会把不好的地方剪掉
l'll cut out the negatives you want.
他们会走的
They'll go.
他们没走
They're not going.
别走
Don't go.
- 你买的螺旋桨吗？ - 什么？
- Have you bought a propeller?  - what?
今天早上你买了螺旋桨，对吗？
You bought a propeller this morning, right?
噢，是的
Oh, yes.
你得帮帮我们
You'll have to give us a hand with it.
- 行了吗？ - 好了，是的
- All right?  - Fine. Yeah.
什么事？
what's it for?
没事，很漂亮
Nothing. lt's beautiful.
如果我有这么大的房子，我就把它挂在天花板上当电扇
lf l had a big room like this, l'd hang it from the ceiling like a fan.
- 你一个人住吗？ - 不
- Do you live on your own?  - No.
或许我会把它像雕刻品一样挂在那里
Perhaps l'll put it there like a piece of sculpture.
那样看起来会很好的，会分解立射光线
lt'll look good there. lt'll break up the straight lines.
- 你要走了吗？ - 很晚了
- Are you going?  - lt's late.
我还会再见到你吗？
Do l see you again?
至少告诉我你的名字，电话号码是多少
well, at least tell me your name or your telephone number.
谢谢你
Thank you.
喂？勇士桥1-259
Hello? Knightsbridge 1 -239.
什么？
what?
不，对不起
No, l'm sorry.
伦？
Ron?
太奇妙了
Something fantastic's happened.
在公园拍的那些照片太奇妙了
Those photographs in the park, fantastic!
有个人想杀某个人
Somebody was trying to kill somebody else.
我救了他的命
l saved his life.
听好，伦，有个女孩
Listen, Ron, there was a girl.
伦，你在听吗？
Ron, will you listen?
奇妙的是…
what makes it so fantastic--
听着，伦，你等等好吗？有人敲门
Look, hang on, will you, Ron? There's somebody at the door.
没想到我们会来，对吗？
You weren't expecting us, were you?
没想到
No.
- 你会煮咖啡吗？ - 我会煮爱尔兰热咖啡，如果你喜欢
- Can you manage to make a cup of coffee?  - l can make an lrish coffee, if you'd like.
好，来吧
Right, come on.
- 她一直像这样吗？ - 像怎样？
- She always like that?  - Like what?
不说话
Doesn't speak.
你叫什么名字？
what's your name?
算了，她的名字有什么用呢？
Forget it. what's the use of her name?
他们在床上叫你什么？
what do they call you in bed?
我只上床睡觉
l only go to bed to sleep.
喂？
Hello?
来看看这些衣服
Look at all these clothes.
不好
No.
- 嘿，这件怎么样？ - 穿上
- Hey, how about this one?  - Put it on.
你呢？随便穿？
what about you? Help yourself.
啊！咖啡！
The coffee!
干什么？
what's happening?
- 怎么了？ - 她身材比我好
- what's the matter?  - She's got a better figure than me!
来，打她，给她一记左钓拳
Go on, whack her. Go on, give her the left hook.
我们一起让你失宠
we'll put you in the ring together.
噢，不！
Oh, no!
抓住她的腿
Hold her legs!
不！不！
No! No!
- 抓住她的腿！ - 不
- Hold her legs!  - No!
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
放开我
Let go of me.
好了，走吧，出去吧
Right, let's move. Out.
- 但是还没拍照呢  - 不，我太累了
- But you haven't taken any photos.  - No, l'm too whacked.
是你们自己的错
lt's your own faults.
明天
Tomorrow.
明天！
Tomorrow!
你刚刚在找什么东西吗？
were you looking for something just now?
没有
No.
你想过要离开他吗？
Do you ever think of leaving him?
不，我不这么想
No, l don't think so.
今天早上我看见一个人被杀了
l saw a man killed this morning.
在哪？
where?
照片里
Shot.
在一个公园
ln some sort of park.
你肯定吗？
Are you sure?
他还在那里
He's still there.
他是谁？
who was he?
某个人
Someone.
怎么杀的？
How did it happen?
不知道，我没看见
l don't know, l didn't see.
你没看见
You didn't see.
没有
No.
你没报警吗？
Shouldn't you call the police?
那是尸体
That's the body.
看起来像是比尔的画
Looks like one of Bill's paintings.
是的
Yes.
你会帮我吗？
will you help me?
我不知道该怎么办
l don't know what to do.
什么事？
what is it?
我想知道他们为什么要杀他
l wonder why they shot him.
我没有问
l didn't ask.
喂，伦？噢，你好，亲爱的，伦在吗？
Hello, Ron? Oh, hello, love. ls Ron there?
不，我只是想带他去个地方，他在哪？
No, l just wanted to take him somewhere. where is he?
好的，我去找他，拜拜，亲爱的
Okay, l'll fetch him there. Bye-bye, love.
再给他们放歌
Give them the song again.
伦
Ron.
来一下，好吗？
Give me a minute, will you?
伦
Ron.
有人被杀了，你…？
Someone's been killed. Now, would you--?
好吧
Okay.
听着，我在公园拍的那些照片…
Listen. Those pictures l took in the park--
我以为你人在巴黎
l thought you were supposed to be in Paris.
我是在巴黎
l am in Paris.
来，吸一点
Here. Have a drag.
我要你看看尸体
l want you to see the corpse.
我们必须去给它拍照
we've got to get a shot of it.
我不是摄影师
l'm not a photographer.
我是
l am.
他怎么了？
what's the matter with him?
你在公园看到什么？
what did you see in that park?
什么都没看到
Nothing.
伦
Ron.